{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"4827","name":"Selden Standard","address":"3921-29 Second Ave","zipcode":"48201","owner":"Woodland St LLC","licenseNumber":"079255","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","coords":"-83.06458,42.34756","geojson":{"id":"4827","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.0645781539999,42.347558803]},"properties":{"name":"Selden Standard","owner":"Woodland St LLC","address":"3921-29 Second Ave","zipcode":"48201","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"High","license_number":"079255","establishmentid":"4827","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"180.0","most_recent_license_date":"4/25/2018"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"5372","name":"Foundation Rock Spirits LLC dba Castalia","address":"3980 Second Ave Unit E","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"2140","name":"Honest John's Bar & Grill","address":"488 Selden St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5126","name":"Will Leather Goods Coffee Shop","address":"4120 Second Ave","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51622663","name":"SheWolf Pastificio & Bar","address":"438 Selden","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"436","name":"Jumbo's Bar","address":"3736 Third St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"4152","name":"Slows To Go","address":"4107 Cass Ave","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5042","name":"Slows On The Go Mobile Kitchen","address":"4107 Cass Ave","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"1337","name":"Old Miami Bar","address":"3930 Cass Ave","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5386","name":"Detroit Royale with Cheese","address":"4163 Cass Ave","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5180","name":"Cinema Detroit","address":"4126 Third St","zipcode":"48201"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"44616","inspectionDate":"2018-12-28T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-301.11","violationDescription":"(A) To prevent food contamination FOOD EMPLOYEES shall properly wash their      hands.\r\n(B) FOOD EMPLOYEES may not contact exposed, READY-TO-EAT FOOD with      their bare hands and shall use suitable UTENSILS such as deli tissue,       spatulas, tongs, single-use gloves, or dispensing EQUIPMENT. (P)\r\n(C) FOOD EMPLOYEES shall minimize bare hand and arm contact with exposed     FOOD that is not in a READY-TO-EAT form. (Pf)\r\n\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Ready-to-eat food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Handled with bare hands","subProblem":"","location":"PREP AREA(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-28T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Suitable utensils or single-use gloves are to be utilized."},{"violationCode":"3-304.12","violationDescription":"During pauses in FOOD preparation or dispensing, UTENSILS shall be stored:\r\n(A) In the FOOD with their handles above the top of the FOOD and the container;\r\n(B) In FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS with their handles above the      top of the FOOD within containers or EQUIPMENT that can be closed, such as      bins of sugar, flour, or cinnamon;\r\n(C) On a clean portion of the FOOD preparation table or cooking EQUIPMENT\r\n(D)  In running water, such as dipper well.\r\n(E)  In a clean, protected location if the UTENSILS, such as ice scoops, are   used only with a FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS; or\r\n(F)  In a container of water maintained at a temperature of at least 135° F.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Dispensing utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly stored","subProblem":"To prevent contamination of food or food related items","location":"ICE MACHINE","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-12-28T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"COOLERS THROUGHOUT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"violationCode":"6-501.11","violationDescription":"PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be maintained in good repair.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities","subItem":"wall(s)","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN (BACK AREA)","subLocation":"Wall(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \r\n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \r\n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \r\n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \r\n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\r\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \r\n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \r\n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\r\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\r\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\r\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\r\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\r\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"","location":"ICE MACHINE","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean as required above."}]},{"inspectionid":"43910","inspectionDate":"2018-06-01T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Complaint","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"GRILL AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"}]},{"inspectionid":"41849","inspectionDate":"2018-04-09T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-301.11","violationDescription":"(A) To prevent food contamination FOOD EMPLOYEES shall properly wash their      hands.\r\n(B) FOOD EMPLOYEES may not contact exposed, READY-TO-EAT FOOD with      their bare hands and shall use suitable UTENSILS such as deli tissue,       spatulas, tongs, single-use gloves, or dispensing EQUIPMENT. (P)\r\n(C) FOOD EMPLOYEES shall minimize bare hand and arm contact with exposed     FOOD that is not in a READY-TO-EAT form. (Pf)\r\n\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Ready-to-eat food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Handled with bare hands","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-04-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Suitable utensils or single-use gloves are to be utilized."},{"violationCode":"3-301.12","violationDescription":"A FOOD EMPLOYEE may not use a UTENSIL more than once to taste FOOD that is to be sold or served.\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"To taste food for sale/service","subProblem":"","location":"COOK LINE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-04-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Utensils shall not be reused to taste food items without proper dishwashing."},{"violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \r\n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\r\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\r\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\r\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\r\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\r\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\r\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Raw animal food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/next to","subProblem":"","location":"COOLERS (BAR)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-04-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store raw animal foods below and away from foods needing little or no further prep."},{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \r\n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \r\n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \r\n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \r\n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\r\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \r\n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \r\n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\r\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\r\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\r\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\r\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\r\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"","location":"ICE MACHINE","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean as required above."},{"violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"GRILL AREA","subLocation":"Cooler (prep)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-204.112","violationDescription":"(A)  In a mechanically refrigerated or hot FOOD storage unit, the sensor of a TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE shall be located to measure the air temperature in the warmest part of a mechanically refrigerated unit and in the coolest part of a hot FOOD storage unit.\r\n(B)  Cold or hot holding EQUIPMENT used for POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD shall be designed to include and shall be equipped with at least one integral or permanently affixed TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE that is located to allow easy viewing of the device's temperature display (EXCEPT, heat lamps, cold plates, steam tables, or other equipment where it is not practical).\r\n(C)  TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be designed to be easily readable.\r\n(D)  FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES and water TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES on WAREWASHING machines shall have a numerical scale, printed record, or digital readout in increments no greater than 1C or 2F in the intended range of use. (Pf)\r\n\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Thermometer(s)","subItem":"refrigeration","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"Cooler(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"3-304.12","violationDescription":"During pauses in FOOD preparation or dispensing, UTENSILS shall be stored:\r\n(A) In the FOOD with their handles above the top of the FOOD and the container;\r\n(B) In FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS with their handles above the      top of the FOOD within containers or EQUIPMENT that can be closed, such as      bins of sugar, flour, or cinnamon;\r\n(C) On a clean portion of the FOOD preparation table or cooking EQUIPMENT\r\n(D)  In running water, such as dipper well.\r\n(E)  In a clean, protected location if the UTENSILS, such as ice scoops, are   used only with a FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS; or\r\n(F)  In a container of water maintained at a temperature of at least 135° F.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Dispensing utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly stored","subProblem":"","location":"ICE BIN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Relocate."},{"violationCode":"6-303.11","violationDescription":"Light of the proper intensity shall be provided as specified.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Lighting intensity","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Less than","subProblem":"","location":"COOLERS THROUGHOUT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Replace."}]},{"inspectionid":"39982","inspectionDate":"2017-09-12T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"GRILL AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-12T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"3-306.11","violationDescription":"Except for nuts in the shell and whole, raw fruits and vegetables that are intended for hulling, peeling, or washing by the CONSUMER before consumption, FOOD on display shall be protected from contamination by the use of PACKAGING; counter, service line, or salad bar FOOD guards; display cases; or other effective means. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Food on display","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Lacking protection","subProblem":"Other effective means","location":"GRILL AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Protect against contamination"},{"violationCode":"7-102.11","violationDescription":"Working containers used for storing POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS such as cleaners and SANITIZERS taken from bulk supplies shall be clearly and individually identified with the common name of the material. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Working containers-toxics","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not labeled as to content","subProblem":"","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-12T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Label containers with common name."},{"violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"GRILL AREA","subLocation":"Cooler (prep)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"37157","inspectionDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Throughout","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store below 41 degrees F."},{"violationCode":"3-203.12","violationDescription":"SHELLSTOCK tags shall remain attached to the container in which the shellstock are received until the container is empty and tags shall be retained for 90 days after the container is empty.  Retained tags shall be kept in chronological order and correlated to the date when shellstock are harvested. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Shellstock","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Identification","subProblem":"More than one tagged/labeled container on display together","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Retain on file."},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"quaternary ammonia","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"DISHWASHING AREA","subLocation":"Lack of Test strips","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Cooler(s)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-09-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null}]}]}],"maxInspectionDate":[{"inspectionDate":"2019-01-31T00:00:00"}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"4827"}}